<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-01T16:40:36-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/</id><title type="html">Alex Kluew</title><subtitle>Personal website and blog of Alex Kluew</subtitle><entry><title type="html">On Discrete Mathematics For Computer Science</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/on-discrete-mathematics-for-computer-science" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Discrete Mathematics For Computer Science" /><published>2018-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/on-discrete-mathematics-for-computer-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/on-discrete-mathematics-for-computer-science">&lt;p&gt;I just ran into &lt;a href=&quot;http://condor.depaul.edu/sepp/ICME-13.Epp.pdf&quot;&gt;“Discrete Mathematics For Computer Science”&lt;/a&gt; by Susanna S. Epp (13th International Congress on Mathematical Education Hamburg, 24-31 July 2016). The piece resonated with me and I decided to note some reflections from my own experience down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I added my own emphasis to the quotes below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The material in discrete structures is pervasive in the areas of data structures and algorithms but &lt;strong&gt;appears elsewhere&lt;/strong&gt; in computer science as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This statement resonates very well with me. During my education, there was a big emphasis on data structures and importance of maths in &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; field. However, there was almost no time spent on the &lt;em&gt;appears elsewhere&lt;/em&gt; part of my studies. This left me frustrated lots of times primarily because I went into software engineering to learn about the application of theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also how I know about Susanna S. Epp and her book &lt;em&gt;Discrete Mathematics with Applications by Susanna S. Epp&lt;/em&gt;. When I found my education exposure was lacking, I started to search for different strategies to learn difficult material. It turns out, if you add a little bit of effort, then you can find an author in your field of interest that can help you learn this challenging material. An author that writes in a way that you can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it is one thing that nobody talks about when you are having a difficult time understanding. The fact that if you are having a hard time studying, then a different solution or approach is needed for you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you know that other approaches exist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you look hard for it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you take an initiative to self-study&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and self-research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[…] an ability to create and understand a proof — either a formal symbolic proof or a less formal but still mathematically rigorous argument—is important in virtually every area of computer science, including (to name just a few) formal specification, verification, databases, and cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[g]raph theory concepts are used in networks, operating systems, and compilers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Set theory concepts are used in software engineering and in databases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Probability theory is used in intelligent systems, networking, and a number of computing applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while I do understand the reference points and examples — I only do so because I went through the system. Looking backwards, when I was learning at the beginning, I recall a big emphasis on data structures and graphs. However, there was no justification besides rote memorization and &lt;strong&gt;needing it for this degree&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This paper explores three reasons for the problem. One is that there has been a reduced emphasis on mathematical proof in the secondary mathematics curriculum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally that was true in my experience. This subject matter was never fully conveyed to me - how proofs form the building blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A study of teacher attitudes by Knuth (2002) indicated that the teachers “viewed proof as appropriate for the mathematics education of a minority of students” and that they saw proof “as a &lt;strong&gt;topic of study&lt;/strong&gt; rather than as a &lt;strong&gt;tool for communicating and studying mathematics&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeap… ding ding ding. That’s how it was conveyed to me in Canadian school system as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A second is that the &lt;strong&gt;ways certain words and phrases&lt;/strong&gt; are interpreted &lt;strong&gt;in ordinary speech&lt;/strong&gt; often differ from the ways they must be interpreted in formal, deductive reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot tell you how much I struggled with this. The cognitive collusion between ordinary speech and formal reasoning. It is tough to get your head around the complicated subject matter. It really is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And these things follow you if you do not grasp them when first learning. As someone who had no English vocabulary, I was studying the new language in parallel as I was getting my education foundation and going through the education system. Not only does it make studying these concepts confusing, it also makes the entire field of Maths as some type of mountain that you cannot climb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of my time memorizing content without understanding. While this approach works to some degree, it almost always fails as you get higher up the knowledge ladder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I did not realize, at the time that I was struggling, was that the road blocks should have signaled to me that I had foundational issues. Instead, I plowed forward without having the full picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I understand this now and it is part of the reason why I read up on things like this in my free time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One of their tasks as students is to learn how to extract the standard interpretation from what is said and written. One of the tasks of instructors is to teach them how to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% did not experience this. In all of my experience so far the instructors believed in rote replication via writing. While this may work for some learning styles, it really did not work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One example is that in everyday speech if-then is frequently interpreted as if-and-only-if.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I find this confusing? Check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Only-if is also routinely interpreted as if-and-only-if.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I find this confusing? Check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In propositional logic the negation of “if A then B” is the conjunction “A and not B,” …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I find this confusing? Check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a bit hard to reflect on this now because I am much more familiar with this subject. But I will try to step back and play around with my thoughts. The author mentions that students seem to reply &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if A then not B&lt;/code&gt; as the common solution to the negation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I can justify that response in my head, my brain wants to say &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if not A then not B&lt;/code&gt; but it definitely doesn’t think &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;not A or B&lt;/code&gt; nor &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;not A and B&lt;/code&gt;. Sure, I know the theory and I know about truth tables. And, if I force myself then I can definitely come up to the solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what I am saying is that it is still challenging to think about these things when you have mental clashes with your everyday speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For instance, a natural response to “If John comes, then the party will be a disaster” is “Don’t worry. If John comes, then the party will not be a disaster. It will be fine.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This takes the language issue a bit further:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;According to the rules of predicate logic, when a statement contains &lt;strong&gt;two different quantifiers&lt;/strong&gt;, they should be interpreted in &lt;strong&gt;left-right order&lt;/strong&gt;. However in ordinary language a statement with both for-all and there-is is typically interpreted in &lt;strong&gt;whatever way makes the most common sense&lt;/strong&gt;. Linguists call this “scope ambiguity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example, the most natural way to interpret the sentence, “There is a lid for every pot” is as “For every pot there is a lid” not as “There is one single lid that will be fit every pot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A third is the difficulties students experience in understanding and using statements involving variables, both in connection with predicate logic and in interpreting certain kinds of mathematical phrases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very true but to me, this stems from issue created in #2 regarding language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the following examples provided in the piece:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What we say — What we mean
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the value of x — the quantity that is put in place of
x&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;as the value of x increases — as larger and larger numbers are put in place of x&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As the value of x increases, the value of y increases. — If larger and larger numbers are put in place of x, the corresponding numbers that are put in place of y become larger and larger
.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;where x is any real number — for all possible substitutions of real numbers in place of x&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Let n be any even number — Imagine substituting an integer in place of n but &lt;strong&gt;do not assume anything about its value&lt;/strong&gt; except that it is an even integer
.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;By definition of even, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n = 2k&lt;/code&gt; for some integer &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; — By definition of even, there is an integer we can substitude in place of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; so that the equation &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n = 2k&lt;/code&gt; will be true. (In fact, there is only one such integer; its value is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n/2&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the function &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x^2&lt;/code&gt; — the function that relates each real number to the square of that number. In other words, for each possible substitution of a real number in place of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, the function corresponds to the square of that number.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; is some real number that satisfies the given property — There is a real number that will make the given property true if we substitude it in place of x.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I respect the author and the work she does, it appears that math education is a loosing battle. I skimmed through author’s article from 1987 (The Logic of Teaching Calculus. In Toward a Lean and Lively Calculus: Report of the Conference Workshop to Develop Curriculum and Teaching Methods for Calculus at the College Level. Ronald G. Douglas, Ed. Washington, D.C.: Mathematical Association of America, 1987, 41-59.) where she outlined similar concerns around logic (only that time it was in the context of calculus).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been more than 30 years and it appears that new students are continuing to struggle with maths. Anecdotally, I hear concerned systems and parents pushing for programming skills while pushing away core maths. If you found math challenging or confusing I encourage you not to give up. You can study it on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start your studies wherever you got confused. There are tests available that can help you narrow it down. Start from grade 1 if you want to. Who is going to judge? Open up khan academy and go to town. Discover the beauty and study on your own time… I did (and I still am).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it wasn’t for Khan Academy, self-studying, youtube, and the people of the internet in general — I am not sure if I would be where I am.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software engineering" /><category term="maths" /><summary type="html">If you found math challenging or confusing I encourage you not to give up. You can study it on your own.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">More frequent updates</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/more-frequent-updates" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More frequent updates" /><published>2018-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/more-frequent-updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/more-frequent-updates">&lt;p&gt;Those of you that know me personally, know that I do a lot of little experiments and I like to reflect. I believe in engineering and science principles. They are at my core and drive me forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I feel like I am not doing a good job in reflecting and sharing that with you. What happens usually is that I open up a blank canvas, such as this one, and just start writing. Usually I have a topic or a direction that motivates me to write. However, I do not consider if I will publish or delete the content at the time of writing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I mean by a blank canvas in September 2018:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018-09-28/Screen-Shot-2018-09-29-at-12.12.33.png&quot; alt=&quot;Blank canvas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I have a lot of written content spread out across various computers, domains, and publications. A lot of this content is not published and, if taken out of context, may seem like a waste of my time. Personally, I find it very difficult to hit that publish button for many reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, writing is cathartic in a sense — the single purpose is to remove the content from my head. When the ideas are out of my head and on a canvas then I can play with them. In my head there is chaos, so I like to consolidate my ideas and to make sense of them. To tease out my views and opinions (and to correct them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you take this into consideration, then perhaps you can see why some of my pieces don’t get my approval and thus never see the light. However, the longer I live on this earth, the more I wish I didn’t hold back and just publish (whether or not it is finished). So, I decided to actively work on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my goals for 2018 was to publish more frequent written updates. The intention was not only to improve the quality of my written content but also to documenting a process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is the end of September. Month #9 is almost done. So how have I been doing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the whole, I have been doing way better than any of my previous years. If you take a look at this year alone, I have published 11 pieces of work so far. Some of them even required a lot of additional work. Gasp!!! One thing for sure — I have been staying consistent. Whatever that means to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I take a look at it this way, then my progress is happening. I am growing and developing. However, during my day-to-day thinking it feels more negative. I feel like I could be doing better in this area. I still find myself falling into the trap of not publishing. Reflecting on this progress definitely helps to stay on track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I think I am doing OK even if it doesn’t feel like that. I give myself the permission to make mistakes, publish more frequent and unfinished work; and continue this journey that I started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened-since-the-last-post&quot;&gt;What happened since the last &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/i-have-to-come-clean-about-my-project&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in June/July/August, I finished the backend &amp;amp; frontend MVP for dailyvibes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the said backend and frontend are not live yet to anyone but you may see some things &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dailyvibes&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;PS, as an aside — I am considering migrating away from github to self-hosted for all of my work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in July, worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://screenhole.net/&quot;&gt;screenhole&lt;/a&gt; and created an MVP for a Mac OS screen recorder functionality. That was a fun experiment that you can view at &lt;a href=&quot;https://screenhole.net/getaclue/~g8U2vv&quot;&gt;https://screenhole.net/getaclue/~g8U2vv&lt;/a&gt; Unfortunately that is not a public feature and is stuck in alpha/beta stage until further notice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in July/August, worked on &lt;a href=&quot;https://keyframes.net/&quot;&gt;keyframes&lt;/a&gt; native Mac app. Was a bit of work but looks nice in my opinion. This work is in &lt;a href=&quot;https://keyframes.net/snapper/beta&quot;&gt;beta&lt;/a&gt; and is available for download.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in August, launched our &lt;a href=&quot;https://cspray.ca/&quot;&gt;physical product&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://theex.com/&quot;&gt;Canadian National Exhibition&lt;/a&gt;. That was intense. Will talk about this more at a later time ;-) but lets just say we are continuing working on this project. This was a FIRST for us and also a BIG deal!!!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Attendance: 1.54 million (2016)&lt;/code&gt; — may hint to you at why. And we made sure to talk to almost everyone that passed by us. I say almost because it was just the two of us.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in September, started to work on news article parser for &lt;a href=&quot;https://elderoost.com/&quot;&gt;elderoost&lt;/a&gt;. One of the current challenges is keeping up to news. I physically read all of the articles manually and filter them manually. This honestly takes a lot of time. If you check the website the latest article was added &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;5 months ago&lt;/code&gt;. I have all of the articles since then I just haven’t processed them yet.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;current working approach:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;get news article link&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;go to the link&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;grab the URL, title, headline, author, date of publication, and the content
            &lt;ul&gt;
              &lt;li&gt;I found a script that helps with grabbing all of this (similar to how some browsers allow you to have a read an html page in plain text if you click a button)&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;put this stuff into postgres db&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;index title and content using elasticsearch&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;for each residence search against this text&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;unfortunately it is not done as I cannot narrow down some edge cases.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-what-am-i-up-to-now&quot;&gt;and what am I up to now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;job search
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After 2 years and some, I think it is time as there aren’t any new opportunities for growth as a software engineer where I am&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The work moved to a new physical location that is more challenging to commute to&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;My school debt is causing me a lot of stress and anxiety… so I’d like to pay this off faster.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I am not being paid what I know I could be for someone with my needed skills
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;I stayed because of the team but that recently got dissolved&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cspray&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dailyvibes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;add user auth functionality on ios
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;make user auth functionality work between ios and server&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;make a sync mechanism between ios and server (probably manual for now and then automate)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;modify the way you share links within iOS (add a new area so it is easier to share)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;share these links from iOS to server (after the user stuff is linked up)&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;provision a server on DO or Linode
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;glue the backend &amp;amp; frontend on this server&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;glue the server to dailyvibes domain&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;elderoost
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;finish news article parser&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;add a notifyer after this is done to manually review&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;figure out monetization&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;… in that order I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I’m going to spend the next little while grinding cracking the coding interview bible and all of the typical hackerrank websites. It is a bit unfortunate that I need to put a pause on the side projects to do this. But it is what it is. (Especially if you want to work for the typical Fortune N company.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for those of you that finished reading this, here is some behind the scenes context to this article. It is an example of a written piece that I ended up &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/would-you-let-your-mother-use-your-software&quot;&gt;publishing&lt;/a&gt;. It started off as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hemingwayapp.com/&quot;&gt;Hemingway app&lt;/a&gt; draft and then, eventually, I approved and transformed it into an article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2018-09-28/Screen-Shot-2018-09-29-at-11.35.50.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample written piece that I ended up sharing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software engineering" /><category term="doubt" /><summary type="html">So, I think I am doing OK even if it doesn't feel like that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I have to come clean about my project</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/i-have-to-come-clean-about-my-project" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I have to come clean about my project" /><published>2018-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/i-have-to-come-clean-about-my-project</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/i-have-to-come-clean-about-my-project">&lt;p&gt;I have something to tell you and come clean about. I haven’t touched my beloved dailyvibes code base since April. And if I am being completely honest, I kind of lost steam in March. (To give you some context, I started thinking about the project in October and working on it last November. Since November I tried to ship something every 2 weeks.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was fine until about March. In March, I felt that I did not like where I was going, I was having a bad time, and I was losing project’s direction. I even had thoughts of abandoning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also knew that my app was stable enough for people to use. Thus, if I was about to abandon my work then at least people would not lose their data. These thoughts allowed me to slow down and to reflect. Afterall, I still care about the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/klf5jH+&quot; alt=&quot;you're going to have a bad time image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I start thinking this way about a project, I become aware that it is a good time to step back and reflect. In other words, it is a good time to see if my time is worth investing into a project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start, I wanted to figure out what was causing me to feel this way. I narrowed it down to the following three issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-i-was-facing-technical-issues&quot;&gt;1. I was facing technical issues.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/ai0zYr+&quot; alt=&quot;subject to technical issues - free image from https://pixabay.com/en/problem-technical-issues-technology-1951987/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I work solo, I did not want to spend my limited time on things that do not move the project forward (in the users eyes). But, it got to a point where I needed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.briantracy.com/blog/time-management/the-truth-about-frogs/&quot;&gt;eat that frog&lt;/a&gt;. It is one of the challenges that comes with indie work. You wear many hats. You are playing the role of a product manager and have to decide on what to work on. Sometimes you have to do the work that you do not want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-i-was-not-happy-with-the-direction-of-the-project&quot;&gt;2. I was not happy with the direction of the project.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/DMndPx+&quot; alt=&quot;lost found searching - image from https://pixabay.com/en/lost-found-lost-and-found-searching-1605501/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the project, I needed to do some market research. I needed to check if this project was worth my interest and time. How did I do my market research? Well, it was very simple. I downloaded all the productivity / todo apps from the Apple App Store and I played with each one of them. I noted down ideas that I liked and things that I did not like. But, by doing that, my phone looks like this now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://d.pr/v/CtydOz&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/b8PU7m+&quot; alt=&quot;my ios screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After playing with each app, I’ve come to realize that most of the apps do the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means to the users is that they have a lot of choice in this saturated category of productivity. In otherwords, they can switch from my product much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this means to me is that I don’t need to stress on competing. I was aligning dailyvibes with other similar apps. This process made me bored and stopped using the app. Dailyvibes started because I was not happy of the solutions. Instead I will focus on building features that will be useful to the end user and to me. I will focus on the product and its quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I took a step back and recorded the actions that I do every day. I interact with the following data structures: tasks to complete today, notes/text snippets, links/bookmarks, gifs / images and photos. One thing that kind of doesn’t fit is positive thoughts / quotes. I need to think some on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will work on integrating these things into dailyvibes and thus forcing me to dogfood my own app. What will make all these things work together is some kind of linking mechanism. I will definitely polish this as time moves on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, users have so much choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-i-did-not-know-what-direction-apple-will-take-mac-os-apps-in&quot;&gt;3. I did not know what direction Apple will take Mac OS apps in.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/LE7TsI+&quot; alt=&quot;marzipan rumours&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next biggest feature for dailyvibes is to create a server component. Which will be then followed by a syncing mechanism of some sort between the server and iOS app. Both of these components, would position me well to create either a a desktop companion app or a web app. I chose to wait until June to make this decision because of WWDC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not decide if I wanted to leverage the iCloud ecosystem and have apple do all the legwork or me. I’ve investigated both options. I decided to roll out my own for three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I know how,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to practice for my personal project, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to have control over my data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that these decisions will also benefit the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also could not decide if I wanted to spend time on a native Mac desktop app or on a web app. I am familiar with web but I am very new to the Mac. I investigated both options. I am deciding, at least for now, to focus on the web app component because I am more familiar with that. Plus, Apple admitted that there will be changes to Mac OS next year. I’ll revisit native Mac app next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is nice to step back and reflect on how far you’ve come with a project. It is good to be mindful. Albeit, I will be first to admit that it is challenging to talk about your project when it is not going as you expect. I am, once again excited, to keep working on the project and I have a better vision moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a nice feeling when you are happy with your decisions. Also, the organic discovery isn’t that bad either:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/MLstRV+&quot; alt=&quot;Q1 results&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/dHUliO+&quot; alt=&quot;Q2 results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re making something, you have to be the first to believe in success of your thing. Do one thing every day that moves the project forward. Everything else will [hopefully] work itself out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: You can download Daily Vibes by searching using your favorite iOS device on &lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033&quot;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt; or from &lt;a href=&quot;https://dailyvibes.ca&quot;&gt;https://dailyvibes.ca&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="doubt" /><category term="mindful" /><summary type="html">I have something to tell you...</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/AoFNPd" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Would you let your mother use your software?</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/would-you-let-your-mother-use-your-software" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Would you let your mother use your software?" /><published>2018-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/would-you-let-your-mother-use-your-software</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/would-you-let-your-mother-use-your-software">&lt;p&gt;Would you let your mother use your software?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/V8kt2K&quot; alt=&quot;Oh and I am not trying to single anyone out in this photo btw&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How about your father? sister? brother? wife? husband? fiancé? grandparents? neighbour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I can immediate hear some of you say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But Alex … you would say …&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;… they would never &lt;em&gt;use&lt;/em&gt; my software… they are not my &lt;em&gt;target audience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or… I would teach them how to use my software properly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Or… I would never let them use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, my dear friend, I would ask that you play along with me in this exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose that the use of your software became mandatory. Suppose your friend or family member had no help or training from you. Suppose they were that user number #1110101 that you did not want to deal with. Take your pick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Are you following along?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are following, at what I am trying to say here, then I hope you can answer yes to my original question with some degree of confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no… you cannot use the typical engineering answer of “it depends”. Sorry, I want a binary response here: yes or no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if your answer is a no then I hope that you might start thinking about these important issues. For example, you could start thinking about why are you leaning towards no? Perhaps, what can you do today to increase your level of confidence? Because you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you call yourself a scientist or an engineer? Do you have some variation of this title? Are you proud to call yourself that? Does it define who you are on a day-to-day basis? If so then you must think about ethics. It is your duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe this belief is naive? Maybe this is not how it works in the real world? Maybe being associated with those things is not enough for such heavy consideration? Maybe we should leave ethics to someone else? We make software to solve some problem and that’s that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too often I see the answer that it is not applicable to me or my work. Too often I see ambivalence and lack of professional care. To me, this cannot be the winning formula moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following software development for the past few years, then you’ve noticed a certain trend by now. A trend of malpractice if you will. Followed by a trend of acceptance or standardization towards such malpractice. And if you dig a little deeper into these trends — they are often, but not always, connected to some lapse in ethics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re of the mind that ethics and business [and software] cannot mix — I call for you to reconsider and have a conversation. I hope the pressure of shareholders and funding money does not blind your mission or your vision. Try to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just because you can do something, should you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you should, then how can you do so while being ethical?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you cannot remain ethical, then the least you can do is own it. Don’t deny it. You are a professional, aren’t you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps our approach to ethics needs a pivot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe ethics, as a field, is too broad of a topic? Too abstract and not applicable?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe, it is time to reframe our delivery on ethics?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time to step back and reduce the scope so that we can understand better?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is me — trying to do that for you. Next time you are working on software just give it a shot and ask yourself this relatable question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;would you let your &lt;strong&gt;_&lt;/strong&gt; use your software?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll let you fill in the blank. Don’t be lazy and do make it relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it because your answer should be yes with some level of confidence. It is 2018 and I am trying to take a gradual approach to this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are use a lot of software every single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And guess what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is only the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just wait until the entire planet, and everyone on it, gets a reliable high speed connection. It is not if but when.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;PS: I know that I am throwing generalities and I hope you can forgive me for the point that I am trying to illustrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;PPS: Sorry for the clickbait title — but how else am I going to get you to read about software ethics? Not trying to single out mothers or family members or friends. I am trying to make a point that you should make your work relatable. Think about your end user. There is an actual person sitting on the other side of your code. And guess what? This person is trusting you and your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@getaclue_1/would-you-let-your-mother-use-your-software-639fb6f0e3d3&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; in April 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><summary type="html">Sorry for the clickbait title — but how else am I going to get you to read about software ethics?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/V8kt2K" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to make perfect iOS screenshots with a clean status bar in 2018</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/how-to-make-perfect-ios-screenshots-with-a-clean-status-bar-in-2018-using-fastlane.tools-and-simulatorstatusmagic" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to make perfect iOS screenshots with a clean status bar in 2018" /><published>2018-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/how-to-make-perfect-ios-screenshots-with-a-clean-status-bar-in-2018-using-fastlane.tools-and-simulatorstatusmagic</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/how-to-make-perfect-ios-screenshots-with-a-clean-status-bar-in-2018-using-fastlane.tools-and-simulatorstatusmagic">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/oV4Piy&quot; alt=&quot;Image for the post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi friends,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;before-we-begin&quot;&gt;Before we begin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I begin, I am assuming you are already running your UITests using &lt;a href=&quot;https://fastlane.tools/&quot;&gt;fastlane.tools&lt;/a&gt;. If not, I would suggest that you get yourself familiarized &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fastlane.tools/getting-started/ios/screenshots/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It saves you lots of time and it is especially indispensable for solo developers like myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-this-article-about&quot;&gt;What is this article about?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is about improving your iOS marketing material: the screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we will go from this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/FuVdCb+&quot; alt=&quot;Starting point&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/7vkqhx+&quot; alt=&quot;Goal of this article&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be using &lt;a href=&quot;https://fastlane.tools/&quot;&gt;fastlane.tools&lt;/a&gt; in combination with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shinydevelopment/SimulatorStatusMagic&quot;&gt;SimulatorStatusMagic&lt;/a&gt; library. SimulatorStatusMagic is used to create the perfect status bar:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9:41 AM is displayed for the time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The battery is full and shows 100%&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On iPhone: The carrier text is removed, 5 bars of cellular signal and full WiFi bars are displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On iPad: The carrier text is set to “iPad” and full WiFi bars are displayed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The text above is taken verbatim from the library’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/shinydevelopment/SimulatorStatusMagic&quot;&gt;description&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-would-you-want-to-do-that&quot;&gt;Why would you want to do that?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, such attention to detail adds extra value to your product by making your marketing material that much better than your competition. If you take a second to scan the Apple App store, the top apps provide some level of consistency in their marketing material. It follows, you should work towards achieving a similar level of consistency because it is not really not that hard. And if you set this up once, it will work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I wanted to the improve the screenshots that I use to market &lt;a href=&quot;https://dailyvibes.ca/&quot;&gt;Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt; in my next update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-did-i-try&quot;&gt;What did I try?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed SimulatorStatusMagic using cocoapods by adding the following line to my Podfile, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;pod&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'SimulatorStatusMagic'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;ss&quot;&gt;:configurations&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Debug'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I found the following &lt;a href=&quot;https://funkenstrahlen.de/blog/2016/04/21/perfekte-ios-screenshots/&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.scottlogic.com/2015/02/25/Using-Snapshot-with-Simulator-Status-Magic-to-generate-perfect-iOS-screenshots.html&quot;&gt;articles&lt;/a&gt; and they gave me good starting points. They were perfect for me because I wanted to use flags in my code like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/CVcNIW+&quot; alt=&quot;How I wanted to import the library&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would allow me to only import SimulatorStatusMagic during fastlane.tools run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, I also envisioned using this one flag throughout other areas of the code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/M0QqzC+&quot; alt=&quot;What I envisioned&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… putting it all together, I wanted something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/B53hS7+&quot; alt=&quot;How I wanted fastlane.tools and SimulatorStatusMagic to work&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But, I could not get it to run exactly like that 😭&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to get this to work. However, as a result of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/search?q=custom_args&amp;amp;type=Issues&amp;amp;utf8=%E2%9C%93&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/issues/4717&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; you need some tweaking in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-my-curent-solution&quot;&gt;So what is my curent solution?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import SimulatorStatusMagic&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;leverage snapshot’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.fastlane.tools/getting-started/ios/screenshots/#advanced-snapshot&quot;&gt;launch arguments&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FASTLANE_SNAPSHOT&lt;/code&gt; is set to true&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;call in code as you wanted
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-rb highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;NSUserDefaults&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;standardUserDefaults&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;boolForKey&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;FASTLANE_SNAPSHOT&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;SDStatusBarManager&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sharedInstance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;().&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;enableOverrides&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;setupScreenshotData&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the code above works … but I will be first to admit that it is not the perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it is currently written, you will need to play the commenting game:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;comment out import SimulatorStatusMagic and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;comment out SDStatusBarManager.sharedInstance().enableOverrides()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;during regular development and do the reverse during fastlane.tools run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… during regular development:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/ptOZ9a+&quot; alt=&quot;What you have to do during regular development&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and … during fastlane.tools run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/DCDj9W+&quot; alt=&quot;What you have to do during fastlane.tools run&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I am familiar with Ruby and Swift, and can get by with Objective-C, I tried to make it work how I wanted and find the source of confusion. I did look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/legacy/library/documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/xcodebuild.1.html&quot;&gt;xcodebuild arguments&lt;/a&gt; and scanned fastlane.tools source &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fastlane/fastlane/blob/master/snapshot/lib/snapshot/test_command_generator_base.rb#L34&quot;&gt;code up to here&lt;/a&gt;. But, since there is only so much time in the day and I work on this during my free time - I did not narrow down the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you have a different solution that allows me to run the code how I wanted, please reach out to me via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;. I will gladly adjust this article to incorporate those changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I hope that you enjoy this working solution. I was puzzled during my research in 2018 and I did not see a solution so hopefully this helps someone in upping their screenshot game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: This article was also published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/how-make-perfect-ios-screenshots-clean-status-bar-2018-alex-kluew/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">Using fastlane.tools and SimulatorStatusMagic</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/oV4Piy" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Improving iOS performance with Xcode and Instruments for dummies</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/improving-ios-performance-with-xcode-and-instruments-for-dummies" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Improving iOS performance with Xcode and Instruments for dummies" /><published>2018-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/improving-ios-performance-with-xcode-and-instruments-for-dummies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/improving-ios-performance-with-xcode-and-instruments-for-dummies">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/eVxYjd&quot; alt=&quot;Image for the post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi friend, is your app running a bit slow? Are you, perhaps, unsure what to do about it? Where do you start to investigate? Perhaps, like me, you started searching 🕵️‍️ in your code for something evident? (Only to realize that you are going down a never ending rabbit hole?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, stress not my friend because Xcode got you covered ✅ and it will help you find your issues (or put you on the right track at least).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a second article that I am writing about an Integrated Development Environment (IDE). The more that I use Xcode, the more I like it 😎 Xcode is really, really awesome. Just give it a try and use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Side note: it &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; took me 182 hours to get to the Instruments panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m actually really surprised at the amount of tooling that is given to you in this wonderful IDE. My software engineering training gave me my introduction to IDEs via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/ide/&quot;&gt;Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://netbeans.org/&quot;&gt;NetBeans&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve spent years using those tools (and don’t get me wrong, they are powerful). But to be completely honest, to this day I will pick anything else but these two. They are ugly, clunky, and not intuitive 🌶&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-i-type-that-paragraph-above&quot;&gt;Why did I type that paragraph above?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because if you have an aversion to IDEs and think that Xcode looks just like the other IDEs, then I am here to tell you that it really is not. Xcode &lt;em&gt;IS&lt;/em&gt; a pleasure to use and I use it every day. (&lt;em&gt;PS&lt;/em&gt;: If you are getting angry while reading this and saying &lt;strong&gt;!?Xcode sucks!?&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t get so upset. I will admit, it is not perfect.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instruments&quot;&gt;Instruments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is this powerful thingy, built on top of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DTrace&quot;&gt;DTrace&lt;/a&gt;, that comes with Xcode. No need to install extra software. Just download Xcode once and you have everything you need. Don’t have internet connection or you don’t want to be connected? No worries, you can still DO your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah… I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s_SOYcYBnGU&quot;&gt;this wonderful youtube video&lt;/a&gt; to get an introduction to Instruments. Apple ofcourse has their own documentation which you can get &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/library/content/documentation/DeveloperTools/Conceptual/InstrumentsUserGuide/index.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following text is basically my brief overview of Instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you open Instruments, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/c280xV+&quot; alt=&quot;Xcode Instruments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can launch Instruments like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/QiJqRR+&quot; alt=&quot;Opening Xcode instruments open&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/PtBZgx+&quot; alt=&quot;Opening Xcode Instruments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I didn’t want to leave you waiting while my slow computer takes its time to compile and open up… but you get the idea)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you do next is kind of interesting. All of the icons that you see above represent the different kinds of tool that you can run on your application. (I think of this screen as a collection of apps for your app). Hopefully you will understand why I say &lt;em&gt;on&lt;/em&gt; your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all of the available options, I’ve only gotten familiar with Activity Monitor, Allocations, Leaks, and Time Profiler. Oh yes, not only are these tools wonderful but the naming conventions are intuitive and grouped by colour. Amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Activity Monitor and Time Profiler are in blue. These blue thingys are used to monitor CPU stuffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allocations and Leaks are in orange. These orange thingys are used to monitor memory stuff. (Guess what this other orange Zombies thingy looks at? Did you guess RAM stuffs? Cool right!!!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be wondering to yourself… all of these thingsys are cool sounding, so what? What do I do with them? Well the cool thing about these thingys is that you can just JUMP in and you will figure things out as you go. It is that easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest that you play with the other tools available. I am going to focus on the Time Profiler for the rest of this article. At this point in the learning, I found it to be the most useful for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Profiler - I’ve been using this for…profiling… time? 🤷‍ Basically, I open it up and it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/yRulLi+&quot; alt=&quot;Time Profiler in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be asking, now what? How about we hit that big Red Record button ⏺ ? Yup, and it will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/zElUrI+&quot; alt=&quot;Time Profiler after hitting record button in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-what-&quot;&gt;Now what? 🤔&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you use your app! What Instruments, or should I say Time Profiler, does in the background is it samples your environment… Time Profiler &lt;em&gt;records&lt;/em&gt; what it sees your app is doing during a specific time interval. Makes sense?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you have ever used software that has some kind of manipulation of a timeline, then you will be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is a &lt;em&gt;snapshot&lt;/em&gt; of how your app behaves, or its environment:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/GPnnjB+&quot; alt=&quot;Time Profiler Sample in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;time profiler records many such samples at a regular interval over time:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/cEMzNa+&quot; alt=&quot;Time Profiler time line in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;until you press the stop button ofcourse:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/A5InKH+&quot; alt=&quot;Time Profiler from start to stop in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-what--1&quot;&gt;Now what? 🤔&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now you get to take off your developer hat 🎩 and play a detective 🕵️‍ … for real… how cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we are exploring the Timing Profiler, we are interesting in timing. You can open up (expand) the tree, that Xcode conveniently made for you, and go exploring 🗺. See which areas or which methods in your code take a long time. It very simple. Just click expand ⏬ and dive 🏊‍ in:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/KohUC7+&quot; alt=&quot;Start exploring Time Profiler in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-know-where-to-start-try-this&quot;&gt;Don’t know where to start? Try this:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click record&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Play with you app as regular user (try various uses case)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop the recording&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then… you can filter specific time intervals!! How cool is that?!?!?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of me recording as I create a new to-do in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dailyvibes.ca/&quot;&gt;dailyvibes&lt;/a&gt; and then filtering various time intervals.
You can really isolate the various time intervals, like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/MDyrNo+&quot; alt=&quot;Example of using Time Profiler in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, to filter you simple Click and Drag on the timeline… just like any other application with a timeline. It is just that simple. And, when you filter, if you notice, the tree changes. Thus you can really get into the nitty gritty details and find out your problems 🚧.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and… and… and you can SAVE this sampling and come back to it later:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/QP4X3Z+&quot; alt=&quot;Saving Time Profiler in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an actual example of me diving deep into the tree 🌲. When you find something juicy, like this:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/G4H042+&quot; alt=&quot;Example of Time Profiler in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can… double click on the method, and it will show you EXACTLY which lines 👀 of code that may be troubling:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/IOa6qa+&quot; alt=&quot;Double clicking on a method in Time Profiler in Xcode&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you have it friends. I’d like you to take away three things from this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xcode is pretty awesome 🔥&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be a digital detective 🕵️‍ and give Instruments a try&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be careful ❌ of premature optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you liked this, please let me know. I like hearing feedback so I can improve.
You can find me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1&quot;&gt;twitters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: I hope I did not offend you with the *for dummies tagline. I love technical documents but I feel like they need a bit of flavour sometimes. I simply want this technical mumbo-jumbo to feel relatable and friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: This article was also posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@getaclue_1/improving-ios-performance-with-xcode-and-instruments-for-dummies-b42a731b5240&quot;&gt;medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">Don't know where to start? Try this</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/eVxYjd" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to call Javascript debugger from Xcode? Can you?</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/how-to-call-js-debugger-from-xcode" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to call Javascript debugger from Xcode? Can you?" /><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/how-to-call-js-debugger-from-xcode</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/how-to-call-js-debugger-from-xcode">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/X7qI5E&quot; alt=&quot;How to call JS debugger from Xcode?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hi-friends&quot;&gt;Hi friends,&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/7zk3ZR&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Vibes Apple Store Screenshots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous release of ⭐️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033&quot;&gt;Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt; 📲, version 1.3.0, I added a natural language date parser. What this basically means that if you enter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;appointment with my accountant tomorrow at 3 pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⭐️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033&quot;&gt;Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt; 📲 will understand what you mean. This is all possible because of the wonderful work done on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/quire-io/SwiftyChrono&quot;&gt;SwiftyChrono&lt;/a&gt;. However, I shipped 🚢 it with some pending things that are needed to be taken care of with the library. Figured I would fix it later down the road since it seems to work as expected 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I’ve decided to tackle the issues and help updating &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/quire-io/SwiftyChrono&quot;&gt;SwiftyChrono&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/WQSc8k&quot; alt=&quot;Github SwiftyChrono PR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internally, SwiftyChrono uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/quire-io/SwiftyChrono/tree/master/Tests/SwiftyChronoTests/JS/en&quot;&gt;javascript&lt;/a&gt; for testing. After the upgrades, I wanted to make sure that the tests work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;javascript-core&quot;&gt;JavaScript [Core]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I began 👀 looking for issues ⛈&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the issues was narrowed down to be in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/quire-io/SwiftyChrono/blob/55f7a642916c24637c8c22d656884c0681b3aa48/Tests/SwiftyChronoTests/JS/en/test_en.js#L1&quot;&gt;this area of the code&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/9mAyJg&quot; alt=&quot;Problem code image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you notice, it is just javascript that is being executed. I know javascript so it should be no problem to debug, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, for starters, how do you debug javascript that is executed from Xcode? How does Xcode run javascript? This leads you down the rabbit hole to find that Apple has nicely introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/documentation/javascriptcore&quot;&gt;JavaScript Core&lt;/a&gt; internally (&lt;a href=&quot;http://nshipster.com/javascriptcore/&quot;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sothe-tldr&quot;&gt;So…the tl;dr&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very easy. Apple has built a nice interaction between Xcode and Safari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The credit for the following steps to this answer goes to &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/43916256&quot;&gt;Rakesh Yembaram&lt;/a&gt; on stackoverflow.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-open-safari-and-enable-developer-menu&quot;&gt;1. Open Safari and Enable Developer Menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open Safari&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enable the Develop menu by going to:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Preferences”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Advanced”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“Show Develop menu in menu bar”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/mnewCo&quot; alt=&quot;Show Develop Menu in Menu Bar of Safari&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-enable-jscontext&quot;&gt;2. Enable JSContext&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to Develop menu
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/fGg3fS&quot; alt=&quot;Develop menu in Safari&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find your simulator or computer agent and enable&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Automatically show web inspector for JSContexts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Automatically pause connecting to JSContexts&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/EPq8qe&quot; alt=&quot;Enable JSContext in Safari&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1010lK7Y&quot;&gt;Download Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-re-run-project-in-xcode&quot;&gt;3. Re-run project in Xcode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my example, I’m just going to simply add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;debugger&lt;/code&gt; keyword to the Javascript file&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/d5zfNe&quot; alt=&quot;added debugger to source code&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then I press run on the tests
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/lpBPFQ&quot; alt=&quot;press run on Xcode test images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I wait until Safari does its the magic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/tLQhEf&quot; alt=&quot;safari doing magic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you go, hopefully now you can see that it is not that difficult to debug any javascript that your app might contain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading and until next time my friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;⭐️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1010lK7Y&quot;&gt;Download Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt; 🚀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,
Alex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="growth" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html">In a previous release of ⭐️ Daily Vibes for iOS, 1.3.0, I added a natural language date parser.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/2PWtsR" /></entry><entry><title type="html">January and February Reflections</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/january-and-february-reflections" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January and February Reflections" /><published>2018-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/january-and-february-reflections</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/january-and-february-reflections">&lt;h2 id=&quot;hi-friends&quot;&gt;Hi friends,&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can’t believe how quickly January and February came and went. I hope you’ve had a productive start to the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/S7arGb&quot; alt=&quot;Calendar image from https://pixabay.com/en/timeline-planner-success-achieve-3168323/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to look back on the amount of work that done in the past two months&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;january&quot;&gt;January&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things happened in January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1010lK7Y&quot;&gt;Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt; is available on the Apple App Store. If you haven’t downloaded it yet, just give it a shot (&lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1010lK7Y&quot;&gt;download&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added a sign up sheet for beta testers:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;You can now sign up to beta test &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dailyvibesapp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@dailyvibesapp&lt;/a&gt; if you like. Now public. For all. Yup... Coming to Store. Soon. Like really soon. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tszKEOVgeS&quot;&gt;https://t.co/tszKEOVgeS&lt;/a&gt; PS. Plz tell your friends too ❤️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/qyPJUrEWS4&quot;&gt;https://t.co/qyPJUrEWS4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alex Kluew 🇨🇦 (@getaclue_1) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1/status/951587276949278720?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 11, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As a result of shipping, started fixing bugs 🐞 here and here&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;finally 😅 fixed this 🐞 bug that has been 😡 annoying me for a while &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dailyvibes?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dailyvibes&lt;/a&gt; yay small 🏆 wins &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dailyprogress?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dailyprogress&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dailyvibesapp?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@dailyvibesapp&lt;/a&gt; January 19 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/tPwhbet4Rj&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/tPwhbet4Rj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alex Kluew 🇨🇦 (@getaclue_1) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1/status/954375575447236608?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;and yes this took some 👩‍💻 work 🙈 b/c of theming ... should be smooth ⛵️ sailing moving ⏩ forward&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alex Kluew 🇨🇦 (@getaclue_1) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1/status/954376036778639360?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;was frustrated with App Delivery … a bunch of times …comes as a benefti of exposure to the Apple Ecosystem I suppose 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;february&quot;&gt;February&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continued incremental improvement of Daily Vibes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated Kickstarter page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;also 🛠 fixed this icon issue &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/VCT80m3HpY&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/VCT80m3HpY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alex Kluew 🇨🇦 (@getaclue_1) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1/status/954381779720269824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding small UI accents that I was longing for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Can’t wait to 🚢 these 💸 awesome updates to you. ⚒ Today shows items due today or are on Today list. 📫 This week shows... you get it 🎉 oh and added quick to view accents 🚀 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dailyprogress?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dailyprogress&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dailyvibes?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dailyvibes&lt;/a&gt; Feb 13 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/UasSlId95m&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/UasSlId95m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daily Vibes (@dailyvibesapp) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dailyvibesapp/status/963579252586221568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 14, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While using DV, I noticed myself wanting to add multiple entries at the same time. So, I wanted to build something in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Starting 🔨 work on adding 🗂 multiple items. This is where we are now 🤓! &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dailyvibes?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dailyvibes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/productivity?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#productivity&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/dailyprogress?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#dailyprogress&lt;/a&gt; Feb 17 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/rlTA3dpMGk&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/rlTA3dpMGk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daily Vibes (@dailyvibesapp) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dailyvibesapp/status/964938263759937536?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 17, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This error took a few days to fix …&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Getting this error when uploading to iTC. Our app has arm64 in UIRequiredDeviceCapabilities. Who broke iTC again…&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ERROR ITMS-90502: &amp;quot;Invalid Bundle. Apps that only contain the arm64 slice must also have &amp;#39;arm64&amp;#39; in the list of UIRequiredDeviceCapabilities in Info.plist.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Andrew Mayers (@jamayers) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jamayers/status/966457450948911104?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 21, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This error also took a few days to correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;There are a lot of responses to &amp;quot;No accounts with iTunes Connect Access&amp;quot; error and yet none have worked so far =(&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Alex Kluew 🇨🇦 (@getaclue_1) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/getaclue_1/status/960690718531571713?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;February 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-store&quot;&gt;Apple Store&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I uploaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1010lK7Y&quot;&gt;Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt; to the Apple App Store simply because I wanted to have it out there rather than keep it under wraps. I figured I would add value to the software as I go. In retrospect, it was a good decision because it allowed me to find value quicker (as opposed to when I was working on the app under wraps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After listening to some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indiehackers.com/forum/show-ih-daily-vibes-ios-80a69b4368&quot;&gt;feedback on IndieHackers&lt;/a&gt; I decided to start working on ASO (Apple Store Optimization). Signed up for Apple’s Ads. Signed up for their Affiliate program. Started researching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-have-learned-so-far&quot;&gt;What I have learned so far:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title matters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Description matters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keywords matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having screenshots ??? apparently matters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having a video ?? apparently matters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Description and other stuff that you have to fill in… doesn’t matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-else-i-have-learned&quot;&gt;What else I have learned?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What you actually put in any of those fields doesn’t really matter. Don’t get attached to your App name, App Description, Keywords or anything else to do with it. This is important for indie developers with no ad budget. Why? Because we want to be found so people use our software.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have a budget then you can pick your Branding carefully and you can ignore what I said above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So, while working on improving Daily Vibes I am also looking at improving my overall marketing. I am going to do it iteratively and learn along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-my-plan-of-attack&quot;&gt;What is my plan of attack?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improve title (Daily Vibes ➡️ Daily Vibes: Life Task Manager)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improve subtitle (Todo List &amp;amp; Life Day Organizer ➡️ To do list, life day organizer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improve keywords; currently haven’t decided:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;to-do, list app, list maker, task list, todo list, list, task, todo, to do, life organizer, daily&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;todo,list,organizer,tracker,task,project,things,productivity,to do,to-do,keep,reminder,day planner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;life organizer, good vibes, daily tasks, daily office, daily calender,
daily lists, daily organizer, lists maker,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make screenshots localized with pretty text (via &lt;a href=&quot;fastlane.tools&quot;&gt;fastlane.tools&lt;/a&gt;) … something like:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/LcaVFa+&quot; alt=&quot;LocalizedScreenshot sample&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;make AND edit AND upload a video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/cmP5EE+&quot; alt=&quot;Video WIP Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improve aforementioned screenshots&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;improve aforementioned video&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these ideas are up in the air while I am writing this post. I am hoping to ship them with next release, hopefully sometime next week. Then, I will have to wait and look at the analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of work goes behind the scenes for a single app. I am beginning to appreciate indie developers and their successful products. You really need to be comfortable with wearing ALL of the hats that make a successful business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, marketing is an uncharted area and I was hesitant to start learning it. But look at me now, I can make icons, promo videos, and start being strategic about growth. It is a journey that I am enjoying but it is challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also paved the road and did all of the necessary paper work to add in app subscriptions. Now I just gotta figure out my strategy in this area ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and in closing news, I wanted to keep to a somewhat relaxed 2 week shipping cycle… and so far I have been sticking to the schedule of regular updates =) I hope I can keep this up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://geo.itunes.apple.com/app/id1332324033?mt=8&amp;amp;at=1010lK7Y&quot;&gt;Download Daily Vibes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading and until next time my friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sincerely,
Alex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="growth" /><summary type="html">I wanted to look back on the amount of work that done in the past two months (January 2018 and February 2018) in iOS indie mobile app development</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://cdn-pro.dprcdn.net/files/acc_603419/S7arGb" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ready to Submit</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/ready-to-submit" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ready to Submit" /><published>2018-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/ready-to-submit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/ready-to-submit">&lt;p&gt;Happy Friday 👋&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is so easy to let this writing to get out of hand even though I promised to write more regularly. I’ve been chugging along with a lot of things since last update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am still have trouble understanding how to use TestFlight&lt;/em&gt;. I have done quite a bit of work over the past few days and I wanted to release it to the beta testers. However, I am currently stuck in this state:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/7jVbKS/Vve27WMfts+&quot; alt=&quot;Stuck on these TestFlights&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/Ade4Dd/XZMSnuzKCa+&quot; alt=&quot;TestFlight Stuck on Ready to Submit Screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically I am stuck just like this person that wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/q/44716499&quot;&gt;TestFlight build on iTunes Connect stuck at ‘Ready to Submit’&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve contacted some fellow iOS developers and am now doing what they suggested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I learn from them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;every new application version gets a review that you need to go through (which is exactly what is happening now from what I understand). I like &lt;a href=&quot;https://semver.org&quot;&gt;semver&lt;/a&gt;, so technically this would be a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1.0.2&lt;/code&gt; version. It has been primarily bug fixes and UI changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;every new build, under a reviewed version, does not have to go through this process (apparently). So, this is what I am currently trying:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/8G17N9/9OFVGZcfuV+&quot; alt=&quot;Trying to make the app live&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While, I am waiting for that to go through, I want to debug and figure out what is wrong with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1.0.2&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;: After writing the original text, the solution did not work. Not sure what I am missing but here is what I’ve done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/oztmDY/7rYtV1OYGc+&quot; alt=&quot;TestFlight process&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it also seems that information from bullet point #2 is funky. I changed the app back to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1.0.1&lt;/code&gt; and changed build to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2&lt;/code&gt; and, as you can see, the app is still in the “Ready for Submit” state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to continue with this and, in mean time, I think I am just going to contact Apple Support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Yes, I did consult &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.apple.com/itunes-connect/developer/#/dev78d0a8f87&quot;&gt;View build status and metrics page&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://help.apple.com/itunes-connect/developer/#/dev3d6869aff&quot;&gt;app build statuses page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish Apple would provide more information on this “Ready to Submit” state because this does not really help me at this point in the process 🤕 Why? Because by clicking on this link:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/Dy4n8t/zHHV2KGmdt+&quot; alt=&quot;Click on this link&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will bring me to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/i0YRH9/sAGc3S3smm+&quot; alt=&quot;Ready to Submit definition from Apple&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which doesn’t really answer how to submit 🤕&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, Daily Vibes is stuck somewhere here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/W9e1HV/LS8BkWOfsq+&quot; alt=&quot;Daily Vibes is stuck in one of these phases&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Alex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="growth" /><category term="TestFlight" /><category term="resources" /><summary type="html">Happy Friday 👋</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting familiar with iOS testing</title><link href="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/getting-familiar-w-testing" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting familiar with iOS testing" /><published>2018-01-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://getaclue.github.io/blog/getting-familiar-w-testing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://getaclue.github.io/blog/getting-familiar-w-testing">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d.pr/i/YgH6dm/ayxzukbu17+&quot; alt=&quot;Testing image from https://pixabay.com/en/software-testing-service-762486/&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a quick post, mainly a reference to some resource I’ve been using to get familiar with iOS testing and refactoring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refactoring is fun because I get to exercise my software engineering muscles. This is one of the reasons that I like Swift so much. I get to apply my software engineering knowledge on my own projects 👏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing on the whole is not difficult in iOS. However, when you add things like CoreData then it becomes a bit more chaotic to filter through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@Dougly/unit-tests-and-test-driven-development-xcode-8-and-swift-3-f6d43ecd4bd4&quot;&gt;Unit Tests and Test Driven Development (Xcode 8 and Swift 3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academy.realm.io/posts/andy-matuschak-refactor-mega-controller/&quot;&gt;Let’s Play: Refactor the Mega Controller!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://computingstories.com/swift%20stories/core-data-wrap-class-mocking.html&quot;&gt;Core Data Wrapper Class, Mocking and Unit Testing in Swift 3!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.natashatherobot.com/updated-protocol-oriented-mvvm-in-swift-2-0/&quot;&gt;Updated: Protocol-Oriented MVVM in Swift 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/flawless-app-stories/how-to-use-a-model-view-viewmodel-architecture-for-ios-46963c67be1b&quot;&gt;How not to get desperate with MVVM implementation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.natashatherobot.com/unit-testing-swift-dependency-injection/&quot;&gt;Unit Testing in Swift: Dependency Injection
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/flawless-app-stories/applying-unit-tests-to-mvvm-with-swift-ba5a79df8a18&quot;&gt;Applying Unit Tests to MVVM with Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/cocoaacademymag/unit-testing-uitableview-2387f3a42b4f&quot;&gt;Unit Testing — UITableView&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swiftbysundell.com/posts/different-flavors-of-dependency-injection-in-swift&quot;&gt;Different flavors of dependency injection in Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/flawless-app-stories/cracking-the-tests-for-core-data-15ef893a3fee&quot;&gt;Cracking the Tests for Core Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nshipster.com/xctestcase/&quot;&gt;XCTest​Case /
XCTest​Expectation /
measure​Block()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/iOSthemes/comments/4zbhnk/question_anyone_know_the_hex_for_the_new_twitter/&quot;&gt;iOS Theme Colours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
Alex&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="software development" /><category term="software engineering" /><category term="software quality assurance" /><category term="productivity" /><category term="growth" /><category term="testing" /><category term="resources" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>